(忆往昔)
《凶鬼恶灵》  作者是卡文·爱德路德
"Supernatural" by Carver Edlund.
卡文·爱德路德的真名字
What's Carver Edlund's real name?
恰克·舒尔利
Chuck Shurley?
谁给你权利来写我们的生活的
Who gave you the rights to our life story?!
总有一天  这些书
One day, these books --
会被称为温彻斯特福音
they'll be known as the Winchester Gospel.
你想知道她是什么吗  克劳力
You wanna know what she is, Crowley?
-上帝的妹妹怎么样  -他还有亲戚
- How about God's sister? - He has relatives?
她一来  大家就变疯狂僵尸了吗
So, what, she shows up, and everybody goes "28 Days Later"?
-这是梅塔特隆  -上帝的书记员
- This is Metatron. - Scribe of God.
你的能量在我们这里  现在你是凡人
We have your grace. You're mortal now.
各种羞辱...
The indignities!
我在找上帝
I'm looking for God.
天启的时候他都没出现
He didn't feel the need to show up for the apocalypse.
他只是不觉得这是他的问题
He just doesn't think it's his problem.
现在为什么就会在乎了
Why would he give a crap now?
我不知道  或许因为那是他妹妹
I don't know, maybe because she's his sister.
你的天选之民在受苦
All your chosen are suffering!
别指望上帝  指望我们自己
Don't count on God! Count on us.
也许现在他会听到我了
Maybe now He'll hear me.
(如今)
(哈利和安妮熟食品店私人财产  不供公众使用)
熏牛肉
Pastrami...
好像是吧
maybe.
我放弃
I give up!
嗯  托托
Yeah, Toto.
我也觉得我们不在地球上了
I got a feeling we aren't on Earth anymore, either.
谁啊
Hello?
卡文·爱德路德
Carver Edlund?
这是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
是家酒吧  事实上
It's a bar. Actually --
才不是什么普通酒吧  大天才
It's not just a bar, genius,
这是老大建的
this is one of the Big Man's constructs.
我在哪都认得出他的手笔
I'd know his work anywhere.
我们曾是好闺蜜呢
We were besties, you know.
我倒不会说...
Well, I wouldn't exactly say --
这是惩罚  是吧
This is some kind of punishment, isn't it?
惩罚我的罪孽
For my sins.
让我永远待在地狱边缘
A limbo where I get to spend eternity
一间烂酒吧里  跟个捉刀作家待在一起
in a crappy bar with a hack writer.
哥们
Dude.
抱歉  恰小克  不是一般的捉刀作家
Sorry, Chuckles, not just any hack writer --
是主的先知
a Prophet of the Lord.
饶了我吧
Give me a break.
至少告诉我这里的啤酒是真的
Tell me at least the beer is real in here.
你真觉得我那么差
You really think I'm a hack?
我艰难地读完了你所有的作品
I have trudged through your complete oeuvre --
不管是出版的还是未出版的
published and unpublished.
我这辈子阅书无数
Of the metric ton of books I've read in my lifetime,
《凶鬼恶灵》都挤不进前一
"Supernatural" didn't even crack the top 10...
万
thousand.
无意冒犯
Respectfully.
你一点也不喜欢吗
You didn't like any of it?
-"家"(参见S01E09)呢  -不
- Not even "Home"? - No.
还有"地狱爆发"(参见S02E21)
Or "All Hell Breaks Loose"?
太矫情了
Way too much melodrama.
然后你还把自己加进了故事里
And then you put yourself in the story?
上帝啊
God!
好吧  这有些道理  有点建设性
Okay, that's fair. Mildly constructive.
不过  那你也不该
Still, it doesn't justify you...
烧掉我的一本书
burning one of my books, though.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
"荒诞故事"(参见S02E15)
"Tall Tales."
你在对着小卡独白(参见S09E18)
You were monologuing it to Castiel,
然后把一本书丢进了火里
and you threw one in the fire.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
抱歉  我总是忘
Oh, I'm sorry. I always forget.
我可以不让人们看到我  除非我想显现
People can't see me unless I want them to see me.
这是挺让人糊涂
It's very confusing.
给你  助视眼镜
Here, visual aid.
戴上  会好点的
Put these on. It will help.
戴吧
Go on, just do it.
是配套的
It's a whole thing.
是你
You.
上帝
God.
[邪恶力量 第11季第20集]
上帝
God.
你回来了
You've come back.
真不敢相信你回来了
I can't believe you've come back.
我无意污蔑《凶鬼恶灵》的
I-I didn't mean what I said about "Supernatural."
绝对是被低估了  应该重启
It's underrated -- due for a reboot.
这间酒吧  也一点不烂
And this bar -- it's not crappy at all.
就像喜剧《干杯》里的那个
It's just like the one in "Cheers."
大家都知道我的名字
Everybody knows my name!
-光线也非常柔和  -行了
- And the lights are very forgiving. - Okay, yeah, please,
别下跪了
all the kneeling and stuff,
这总让我觉得特别不舒服
it's always made me deeply, deeply uncomfortable.
别叫我上帝  好吗
Just don't use the G-word, okay?
就喊我恰克吧
Just -- Just call me Chuck.
恰克
Chuck?
Chuck.
我需要来杯更烈的酒
I think I need a stiffer drink.
太好了  我们正需要西装
Oh, perfect. We're gonna need our suits.
你查到阿玛拉的线索了吧
Tell me you got something on Amara.
希望不大  但时间紧迫嘛
Uh, it's a long shot, but clock's ticking, right?
阿玛拉在不知怎么折磨路西法呢
Whatever Amara's doing to Lucifer.
-还顺便暴揍小卡  -是啊
- Yeah, beating on Cass in the meantime. - Yeah.
爱达荷州  希望泉镇  一个韦斯·库珀
Uh, Hope Springs, Idaho. A guy named Wes Cooper
杀死一名同事后自杀
killed himself after killing a co-worker.
据报告称  没人知道原因
According to the reports, though, nobody knows why.
据说  他原本好端端的  然后突然
Apparently, he was a perfectly happy guy, and then...
-发狂了  -怎么  附身吗
- snap. - So, what, possession?
或者是被吃了灵魂
Or he was soulless.
线索不多  但鉴于现状  我也接受了
It ain't much, but given what we've got, I'll take it.
嗯
Yeah.
给你
There you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
哥们  别再用啤酒熨我的衬衫了
Dude, quit ironing my shirts with beer!
你最近如何啊
So, what you been up to?
我超级忙的
Oh, I've been super busy.
是啊  我旅行来着
Yeah, I traveled.
我建立了一个博客  大都是放些猫的照片
I started a blog. Mostly just pictures of cats.
猫咪太可爱了
They're so cute.
对了  我还注册了阅后即焚账号
And, uh -- Oh, I signed up for Snapchat.
我还开始写新系列书了
A-And I started a new series of books.
是的  《革命》
Yeah. "Revolution."
但我觉得没什么前途
But I don't think it's going anywhere.
-《革命》  -是的
- "Revolution"? - Yeah.
《凶鬼恶灵》
"Supernatural".
或许你不太会起标题
Maybe titles aren't your thing.
你说得有理
You're not wrong.
但你为什么要进入恰克的身体
But why did you put on the Chuck suit in the first place?
你是怎么想的啊
How did that make any sense to you?
我喜欢前排看戏
I like front-row seats.
我想藏在眼皮底下
You know, I figured I'd hide out in plain sight.
而且  演戏是很有意思的
You know, plus, you know, acting is fun.
的确是奥斯卡级的表演
Well...it's an Oscar-worthy performance.
但怎么会没人知道
But...how did nobody know?
那个护身符怎么说
I mean, w-what about that amulet thingy?
你跟我说过
Y-You told me about it, some...
是在你面前会发光的咒符
silly charm that burned brightly in the presence of you.
-这个吗  -对
- You mean this? - Yes!
迪恩就有个
Dean had it.
还有你的宠儿  卡西迪奥
And your fav -- Castiel.
-他们接近你的时候  怎么  -我给关掉了
- They were around you. How did it never - I turned it off.
瞧
See?
我真的该把这个放好
I should really put this away.
你绝想不到这东西一直放在了哪里
You'll never guess where this thing has been this entire time.
我才不在乎那个难看的破玩意呢
Look, I don't care about that ugly old thing
或是你为什么要到平民之中体验生活
or why you were slumming it with the plebes.
我们说点要紧的吧
Let's brass some tacks already, okay?
你什么都看得见  听得见
You see and hear all.
你知道我这几年来
You know what an absolute piece of garbage I've been
多人渣
the last couple of years.
你带我过来是想毁灭我吗
Did you bring me here to destroy me?
你知道人类最伟大的创造是什么吗
You know what humanity's greatest creation has been?
音乐
Music.
还有玉米片奶酪
That and nacho cheese.
就连我都无法想出那么美味的东西
Even I couldn't have dreamt up that deliciousness.
但音乐
But music...
是魔法
is magic.
这个地方曾创造出过很多了不起的音乐
A lot of remarkable music was created in this space.
酒吧餐厅
B.G.'s Canteen.
虽然不如结局或煤气灯有名
Now, it's not as well-known as the Bitter End or the Gaslight,
但有些了不起的音乐人正是在这个舞台上起步
but some amazing musicians got their start on this stage.
我希望我们能沾染一点那份魔法
I'm hoping that you and I can tap into some of that old magic
完成我几个月前开始进行的创作
and finish what I started a few months ago.
(上帝  一本自传)
你在写自传
You wrote your autobiography.
算是吧
Ish.
就是写了几章  结构比较松散
I mean, there are chapters, it's kind of a loose structure,
说不好  还缺了点什么
uh, but, I don't know, something's missing.
我遇到瓶颈了
I'm -- I'm stuck.
你想重组乐队
You want to get the old band back together.
列侬和麦卡尼  重新上路
Lennon and McCartney ride again.
我算是综合了列侬和麦卡尼
Well, I'm kind of Lennon and McCartney, so...
但每位作家都需要个好编辑
But every writer needs a good editor.
我最棒的一些作品都是与你一起写的  梅塔特隆
I did some of my best work with you, Metatron.
那么我又能做天使了吗
Does this mean I get to be an angel again?
呵呵
Yeah, right.
不  那个你别指望了
No, no, that's never -- never happening.
-这恐怕是明智的  -我也觉得
- That's probably a good call. - I think so.
那么
Well...
我们开始吧
...let's do this.
多谢联调局对此案的兴趣
Appreciate the FBI taking an interest in this case.
我们这一代不常出这种事
We don't really see things like this around here.
我可以下班吗  治安官
Hey, you mind if I knock off, Sheriff?
我猜猜  阿特回来了
Let me guess -- Art's back?
新婚燕尔
Newlyweds.
带格里尔探员去找法医报告  然后就能走了
You can head home after you show Agent Greer the M.E. files.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, Sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
韦斯·库珀那边查到什么了
What do you have on Wes Cooper?
我问了他的家人朋友
I talked to his friends, family.
没人能想明白他为什么要这么做
Nobody can make heads or tails of why he did this.
我们有证人在韦斯自杀前听到了他说话
We have a witness who overheard Wes before he took his own life.
他说了一些不像他会说的话
He was saying things that sounded out of character.
是吗  怎么说的
Yeah? How so?
韦斯说他的生命毫无意义
Wes said that his life was meaningless,
没人爱他
nobody loved him.
就好像他所有的负面情绪
It was like every negative thought he had ever had
都爆发了出来
came spilling out.
问题是
The thing is...
我认识韦斯的妻子  我们是一个唱诗班的
I knew Wes' wife. We sang in choir together.
她对韦斯的爱至死不渝
She loved Wes till the day she died.
真不知韦斯为什么要那么说
I don't know why he'd say anything like that.
还有这个
And then there's this.
等等
Hold on a second.
我见过这样的情况
I've actually seen something like that before.
警官  告诉我
Deputy, tell me,
小镇最近出现过什么奇怪现象吗
have you noticed any strange phenomena around town?
硫磺味儿  或者断电
Uh, sulfur smells or power outages?
或许莫名其妙的雾
Maybe an unexplained fog?
没有
No, sir.
希望泉永远阳光
It's always sunny in Hope Springs.
至少  以前是的
At least, it used to be.
你着急吗
Are you in a hurry or something?
赶截稿日期
I'm on a bit of a deadline.
跟我说个大致  第一印象
Just give me some broad strokes, first impressions.
说吧
Come on, hit me.
挺好的
It's good.
真的很好
Real good.
天呐
Oh, man.
你不喜欢
You hate it.
什么  不是的
What? No.
我喜欢  很喜欢
I love it. Love it.
我上次在编辑脸上看到这副表情
Last time I saw that look on an editor's face,
我刚交出了《虫子》的书稿
I'd just handed in "Bugs""
得了
All right, come on.
这里很安全  畅所欲言
Safe place.
细节是故事好坏的关键
Details are what make a story great.
这书缺乏细节
This is lacking in some details.
完全没有
Like all of them.
"时间之初  有我"
"In the beginning, there was me."
这不是细节吗  多么吸引人啊
Boom -- detail. And what a grabber.
我就迷上了  我还是亲历者呢
I mean, I'm hooked, and I was there.
我也迷上了  但是
I'm hooked, too, and yet...
需要细节
details.
时间之初时  你不是一个人
You weren't alone in the beginning.
你妹妹也在
Your sister was with you.
谁在乎她啊
Who cares about her?
首先  我在乎
Me...for starters.
我想你应该知道她...
I assume you're aware that she's...
出来活动了
out and about.
晒饱了太阳  修养好了
Tanned, rested, and ready.
你就是因为这个才回来了  是吧
I mean, that's why you're back, right?
这不是她的故事
This isn't her story.
是我的
It's mine.
我以为你要早点回来呢
I thought you were coming home early.
对不起  写文件来着
I'm sorry. Paperwork.
那是跟着你从镇上过来的吗
That follow you in from town?
亲爱的  你先进去  我要报告一下
Honey, you want to head inside while I call this in?
就是雾啊
It's just fog.
你知道我代表法律吧
Hey, you know I'm the law, right?
里面见  警官
See you inside, Deputy.
别忘了你的手铐
Don't forget your cuffs.
调度  这里是3W56
Hey, dispatch, this is 3-William-56.
听得到吗
You got your ears on?
你不是下班了吗  警官
Aren't you done for today, Deputy?
是的
I am.
听着  我知道听起来可能很怪
Listen, I know this might sound odd,
但有股浓雾往我这边来了
but there's a heavy fog headed my way.
天气预报里说了吗
We expecting any weather like that?
没有  晚上万里无云的
No, it's supposed to be clear skies all night.
那么糟吗
That bad?
告诉你  里面可有些猛料
I'll tell you, there's some great bones in there.
我在想缺了什么
I'm thinking what's missing --
或许别去管细节了  考虑下平衡
maybe less about detail and more about balance.
什么意思
How do you mean?
你强调错了重点
You're giving the wrong stuff too much real estate.
比如关于做恰克的章节
Like that chapter about being Chuck.
怎么了
And what about it?
你解释清楚冯内古特行为艺术那套之后
Once you've explained the Vonnegut performance art...
就打住吧
that should be it.
其余的没人会在乎
No one cares about the rest.
我作为恰克干过不少了不起的事
I did some great stuff as Chuck.
我跟你说了  我建了博客
I mean, I-I told you about my blog.
是啊  对了
Oh, right, yeah. Right.
你的猫照博客
Your, uh -- Your cat-pic blog.
是啊  他们特别可爱
Yeah, they're super cute.
-是啊  -这是一个
- Yeah. - So there's that.
-我还一直在旅行  -嗯
- And, uh, I traveled a lot, you know. - Right.
还有  我还约会了
And, uh, I dated.
交了几个女朋友
Yeah, I had some girlfriends.
几个男朋友
Had a few boyfriends.
我还学会了弹吉他
And I learned how to play guitar.
嗯
Yeah.
这让你看上去像个
That, you know, makes you seem like
很接地气  可爱的人
a really grounded, likable person.
有什么不对
Yeah, what's wrong with that?
你既不接地气  也不是人
You are neither grounded nor a person!
-你是说我还算可爱  -不不
- So you're saying I'm likable. - No, no.
我是说  恰克的章节
I am saying the chapter "Chuckle""
花了那么多笔墨  却挤掉了
is devouring pounds of pages at the expense of...
更有趣的东西
juicier stuff.
人们真正想看的东西
Stuff that people might actually want to read.
比如呢
Like what?
比如
Well, like, uh...
大天使
Like the archangels.
你就在这里写了两段关于他们的
I mean, you have got maybe two paragraphs on them in here.
就完了
And that's it!
你不觉得该多讲他们两句吗
Don't you think they deserve a few extra words?
尤其是你的最爱  路西法
Especially your favorite -- Lucifer?
他不是我的最爱
He wasn't my favorite.
他帮你打败了阿玛拉
He helped you defeat Amara.
你把血印托付给了他
You trusted him with the mark.
-你要他向人类低头时  -他拒绝了
- And when you asked him to bow to mankind - He refused.
他反叛了
He rebelled!
并因此破坏了圣诞节
And in doing so, kind of wrecked Christmas.
那里面都写了
Okay, all that's in there.
除了圣诞节的那部分
Except the -- the bit about Christmas.
如果你说  阿玛拉不能写  好吧
If you say that Amara is off limits, fine.
但你知道  每个伟大的英雄
But you know every great hero
都是他或她的恶人定义的
is defined by his or her villain.
路西法不是恶人
Lucifer was not a villain.
他是
He -- He's...
他从前不是恶人
H-He wasn't a villain.
好吧
Okay.
说实话
Real talk.
这里还是能畅所欲言的安全地方吧
Th-This is still a safe place, right?
史上最安全的
Safest place ever created.
好吧
Okay.
有两种回忆录
There are two types of memoir.
一种是诚实的
One is honest...
一种  不怎么诚实
the other, not so much.
真话和杜撰
Truth and fairy tale.
你是想写基斯·理查德斯《人生》那样的大作
Now, do you want to write "Life" by Keith Richards
还是想写
Or do you want to write
布莱恩·威尔逊《那多妙》那样的热曲
"Wouldn't It Be Nice" By Brian Wilson?
我想讲真话
I want to tell the truth.
那你就得好好忙活了
Then you've got some work to do.
这本书毫无启示
There are no revelations in this book!
考虑到你的身份  这太怪了
And that's weird, given who you are.
没有新信息  没有灵魂倾诉
There's no new information, no soul-bearing.
因为我没有灵魂
That's because I don't have a soul.
是啊
Right!
但是  灵魂是你发明的
But you invented them.
你发明了灵魂
You invented souls!
灵魂啊
Souls!
解释一下这点
Try shining a light on that.
你对此作何感受
How did that make you feel?
恶心
Nauseous.
告诉你  不行
You know what?! No.
这不是上...帝说的话
That is not G-O-D talking.
那是恰克说的话
That's Chuck talking.
我明白  你在地球上时  得完全进入角色
And I get it -- when you were on Earth, you had to go full method.
你现在该回归自我了
Well, it's time for you to get back into character.
我就是这样
This is me.
是吗
Really?
这
This --
这堆自我怀疑和无能会淹没世界吗
This pile of self-doubt and nebbishness flooded the Earth?
先是毁灭了所多玛  然后又降罪蛾摩拉
Followed up Sodom with a blockbuster Gomorrah?
造物与惩罚不相上下
Created as much as he punished?
不
No!
我曾经为之工作的那个人  是个狠角色
The guy I worked for -- total badass!
是的  他有时挺浑的
And yes, he could be a dick.
那人
Now, that guy...
才有故事可讲
had some stories to tell.
也要为很多事负责
And he has a lot to answer for.
好吧  那
Okay, so...
我该怎么办
...what do I do?
拿面镜子照照  让我们看到你是谁
Hold up a mirror and show us who you are.
毫无遮掩
Warts and all.
为一个读者而写
Write for an audience of one --
你自己
you.
像没人在看那样忘我舞蹈
Dance like no one else is watching.
是啊
Yeah.
我无论如何都会帮你的
I'm gonna help you either way.
但你得选好道路
But you've got to pick a lane.
理查德斯还是威尔逊  恰克
Richards or Wilson, Chuck?
理查德斯  绝对的
Richards -- all the way.
(霍华德郡  法医部)
抱歉吵醒了你们
Sorry I woke you boys.
不不  没事
No, no, it's all right.
跟我们说说情况吧
Just, uh, why don't you tell us what happened here?
哈里斯今早没来上班
Harris didn't show up for work this morning.
我们打了电话  呼叫她车台  毫无回应
We called, tried her CB, nothing.
所以我就过来看看
So I swung by here.
在厨房地板上发现了阿特
I found Art on the kitchen floor,
哈里斯的猎枪就在他身旁  她...
Harris' shotgun right next to him. She...
看来哈里斯警官
It looks like Deputy Harris
近距离冲她丈夫脸上开了一枪
shot her husband point-blank in the face,
然后离开了现场
then left the scene.
这几天来
Did you notice anything off
哈里斯警官有什么奇怪表现吗
about Deputy Harris' behavior the last couple days?
没有  完全没有
No. Nothing at all.
你最后收到她消息是什么时候
When was the last time anyone heard from her?
昨天最后一次呼叫调度
Called in for the last time yesterday.
提到了
Said something about...
看到浓雾滚来
seeing some fog rolling in.
不知道她为什么会在乎天气
I don't know why she cared about the damn weather.
能联系一下那位调度员吗
Would you get in contact with your dispatch officer?
如果她再接到
Tell her to let us know
这样的报告要告诉我们
if she gets any more reports like that again.
-真的吗  -以防万一
- You serious? - Yeah, just to be safe.
-你知道哈里斯现在可能在哪吗  -不
- And do you have any idea where Harris might be now? - No.
但我们可以在办公室追踪她的车
But we can track her vehicle from our office.
这个
Oh, this!
这才像话
This is what I was talking about.
"第10章  我为何从不回应祈祷
"Chapter 10 -- Why I Never Answer Prayers,
而且你该为此庆幸"
and You Should Be Glad I Don't."
第11章  "神助的真相
And chapter 11 -- "The Truth About Divine intervention
以及我尽力回避它的原因"
and Why I Avoid It at All Costs."
-好多了吧  -简直太棒了
- Better, right? - It's gold!
有点愤怒  有点怨恨
Kind of angry with a side of bitter,
但是真实的
but, hey, it's real.
好了
Now...
我不想过分  但既然你写得正顺手
not to overstep my bounds, but since you're on a roll,
有件事我一直想知道
there's one thing that I've always wondered.
或许能写出不错的一章来
Maybe it will make a good chapter,
-甚至一整本书  -说
- maybe even a whole book. - Shoot.
为什么
Why?
具体点
Can you be more specific?
我经常听到这个问题
I kind of get that question a lot
指什么的都有
about pretty much everything.
你为什么创造生命
Why did you create life?
我觉得孤单
I was lonely.
你妹妹的陪伴不够吗
Your sister wasn't company enough?
我是生
I am being.
她是无
She's nothingness.
这是构不成有趣的两角戏的
It's not exactly the makings of a fun two-hander, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
但你不是只创造了一个大天使
But you didn't stop at one archangel
或是一堆天使
or a handful of angels.
你创造了整个世界
You created worlds.
那是犯蠢
I was stupid.
天真
Naive.
我以为如果我能让妹妹明白
I thought if I could show my sister
这世界不止是我们两个
that there was something more than just us,
有比我们更好的东西  那她或许会改变
something better than us, then maybe she'd change.
或许她会
Maybe she'd stop...
有所改变
being...her.
但是
But...
每次我建个新世界
every time I'd build a new world...
她都要毁掉
she'd destroy it.
所以你和你的大天使
So you and your archangels...
就把她关了起来
locked her away?
你就开始不受限制地创造了
And you got down to unfettered creation.
至少是尽力一试了
Tried to, anyway.
但是
But...
这是我创造的  最接近比我和妹妹
this was as close as I got to something as good as or better
还好的东西了
than me or my sister.
国家公园体系吗
The National Park system?
大自然
Nature.
看看大自然自己都创造了什么
I mean, look what nature created on its own.
而且  睿智的大自然知道
What's more, nature's smart enough to know
有些东西是无法修复的
that sometimes, there's no fixing things.
有时候你只能抹去一切重启
Sometimes you just have to wipe the slate clean.
抹去一切重启
Wipe the slate clean.
是啊
Sure.
自然选择
Natural selection.
好时光啊
Good times.
当然  在你这里是淹没地球  但建艘船
Of course, in your case, that means flood the Earth,
带足东西的意思
but build and stock a boat.
换个面  重新开始
Start over fresh on the B-side.
如果阿玛拉抹去重启  就把什么都毁了
If Amara wipes the slate, the slate's destroyed.
一切都会被毁
Everything is destroyed.
你所有伟大的作品  永远失落
All your great work... lost forever.
那我们该去散散步
We should take a stroll, then.
最后一次享受这美景  趁它还没消失
Enjoy it all one last time... before it's all gone.
(系统错误  申请未找到)
我搞不明白  哈里斯
I can't make heads or tails. Harris is...
原来是负责我们电脑的
was our computer person.
我试试吧
Can I give it a shot?
治安官
Sheriff?
马特和艾米刚打来
Matt and Emmy just called in.
说看到贾斯帕山附近有浓雾
They said they saw some fog rolling in by Jasper Hills.
-他们说雾往哪边来了吗  -向西来镇上了
- Did they say where it was headed? - West towards town.
叫他们回来  进入室内
Okay, call them back, tell them to get inside,
关上门窗  封紧了
shut their windows or doors and seal it up,
千万远离浓雾
and stay the hell away from that fog.
并通知镇上每个人
Then get the word out to everybody in town
-他们也得这么做  -等等
- they need to do the same damn thing. - Hold on.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我和我搭档见识过这种情况  好吗
My partner and I have seen this before, okay?
韦斯  哈里斯警官是被浓雾里的东西感染了
Wes, Deputy Harris were infected by something in this fog.
我知道这听上去很疯狂
Now, I know it sounds crazy --
不  听上去我们该找疾控中心
No, it sounds like we should call the CDC.
-没时间了  -找到哈里斯警官了
- There's no time for that. - Found Deputy Harris.
(詹·哈里斯警官)
她在主街  往这边来了
She's on Main Street, heading right this way.
我们去对付哈里斯
All right, we'll handle Harris.
一定把话传出去
Just please, get the word out,
叫大家都待在室内
tell everybody they need to stay inside,
封好门窗
seal up their windows, their doors -- everything.
快去
Do it.
把他们赶走
Hey, get them out of here.
联调局  格里尔探员  请你们马上进入室内
Agent Greer, FBI. I need you to get inside immediately.
快去
Go.
我想自杀
I tried to kill myself.
但她不让
But she won't let me.
她有话要我转达给你  迪恩·温彻斯特
She has a message -- for you, Dean Winchester.
阿玛拉  她在这儿吗
Amara? Is she here?
不
No.
但自从我吸入了那浓雾
But her words have been echoing in my head
她的声音就一直在我脑袋里回荡
every since I took a breath of that fog.
是她叫你杀你丈夫的吗
Did she tell you to kill your husband?
我看着自己动手的
And I watched myself do it.
好的  听我说  这是感染
Okay, listen to me, this is an infection.
放下枪  让我们帮你
Put the gun down. Let us help you.
不是感染
It's not an infection.
她说这是镜子
She says it's a mirror.
她要让我们看到真相
She's showing us all the truth.
黑暗
Darkness.
光明只是谎言
The light was just a lie.
这一切很快就会结束了
It will all be over soon.
他不会救他们的
He's not gonna save them.
一切都会消逝
It's all going away...
彻底毁灭
forever.
但你不会  迪恩
But not you, Dean.
迪恩
Dean?
Dean!
大自然  是神圣的
Nature? Divine.
人性  是恶毒的
Human nature -- toxic.
他们确实喜欢搞破坏
They do like blowing stuff up.
是啊
Yeah.
最糟的是  他们还打着我的名号
And the worst part -- they do it in my name.
然后又来找我哭诉
And then they come crying to me,
求我原谅  让我善后
asking me to forgive, to fix things.
从不承担一点责任
Never taking any responsibility.
那你的责任呢
What about your responsibility?
我承担责任了啊  我离开了
I took responsibility... by leaving.
辅助轮早晚是得拿掉的嘛
At a certain point, training wheels got to come off.
没人喜欢步步紧盯的父母
No one likes a helicopter parent.
阿玛拉呢  她是你妹妹
What about Amara? She's your sister.
我也为她承担了责任
I took responsibility for her, too.
把她锁了起来  而且很不容易呢
Locked her away -- barely, I might add.
不过是谁放她出来的
And who let her out?
温家兄弟
Sam and Dean Winchester,
可他们在试图弥补
but they're trying to fix that.
你知道我喜欢他俩
You know I love those guys,
但要是迪恩还是恶魔
but the world would still be spinning
世界本会运转如常
with Demon Dean in it.
可萨姆就是接受不了  对吧
But Sam couldn't have that, though, could he?
所以阿玛拉出来了怎么能怪我
And so how is Amara being out on me?
不怪你
It's not.
可你以前帮过温家兄弟
But you helped the Winchesters before.
帮他们  我是救了他们的小命
Helped them?! I've saved them!
我都数不清重塑了卡西迪奥多少次了
I've rebuilt Castiel more times than I can remember.
瞧瞧我什么下场
Look where that got me.
那你就要让阿玛拉赢吗
So you're just gonna let Amara win?
轮到她大放异彩了
It's her time to shine.
那我们为啥还要写你那傻逼回忆录
Then why the hell are we working on your stupid memoir?!
你觉得那很傻逼吗
You think it's stupid?
不  我觉得要写一本
No, I think it's stupid to write a book
根本没人能读到的书才傻逼
nobody is gonna be around to read!
你说只为一位读者而写  我
You told me to write for an audience of one -- me.
我觉得总算说到点子上了
And I think we're finally getting somewhere.
她一回来你就开始写了  是吧
You started writing the second she came back, didn't you?
难怪你要赶截稿日期呢
No wonder you're on a deadline!
现在我知道你为什么要伪装在
Now I understand why you're masquerading
那具可悲的皮囊里了
in that sad little meat suit!
跟你创造这怀旧酒吧的理由一样
For the same reason you created this nostalgic bar
好写你的巨著  你是在躲藏
to write your masterpiece in -- you're hiding!
好吧
Okay.
首先  这份天赐
First of all, this gift...
超级可爱
is super cute.
其次  我没躲着
Secondly, I'm not hiding.
我只是喜欢这里的气氛
I just like the ambiance in here.
你说的
You said...
这是史上最安全的地方
the safest place ever created.
是你自己创造的
Created by you...
保护你不受阿玛拉的伤害
to keep you safe from Amara!
她在这里没法碰你  对吧
She can't touch you in here, can she?
你不高兴  我理解
You're upset. I-I understand.
你说出来挺好的
And it's good to let it out.
但咱们还是先专注写完我的书吧
But, uh, let's focus on, uh, fi, shing my book.
知道吗  我之前是个挺糟的上帝
You know, I was a crappy, terrible god.
我的工作基本就是随便改写一下
My work was pretty much a lame, half-assed rewrite
你的壮举
of your greatest hits.
但起码我从来不是个懦夫
But at least I was never a coward.
这就对了
There he is.
这才是我认识喜欢的那家伙
That's the guy I know, the guy I love.
我还记得第一次见到你时
I remember the first time I saw you.
所有天使都吓坏了  可我没有
All the angels were terrified, but I wasn't.
你散发的光的感觉
The feeling of your light was...
难以名状
was just beyond measure.
之后的事更是超乎想象
And then the unthinkable.
你选了我帮你写碑文
You picked me to help you with your tablets.
你只是我进屋时
You were just the closest angel to the door
离门口最近的天使
when I walked into the room.
你没什么特别的  梅塔特隆
There's nothing special about you, Metatron.
当时没有
Not then...
现在也没有
not now.
好了
Now...
我被人冠以过很多名头
I've been called many things --
缺席的父亲  狂怒的怪物
absentee father, wrathful monster.
但懦夫...
But coward...
我不是在逃避
I am not hiding.
我只是受够了
I am just done
目睹我的实验的失败
watching my experiments' failures.
你是说你自己的失败吧  恰克
You mean your failures, Chuck.
你想看吗  请随意
You want to watch? Be my guest.
据报此前天空万里无云
Reports are that there wasn't a cloud in the sky,
但总所周知  现在出现了一股浓雾
but as we know, a dense fog did roll in.
而且许多市民都感受到了
And many citizens also are feeling
这股雾给他们带来的某种影响
some sort of impact from this fog
这让我们相信雾中有...
leads us to believe that there is some sort of...
要我说的话  这些都是重播
If you ask me, they're all reruns.
应接不暇
...have been overwhelmed...
国民警卫队已经介入
as the National Guard has been brought in.
快离开这里  快
Hey, you got to go. Get!
小甜心
Hey, sweetheart.
我们得带你离开
Okay, we're gonna get you out of here.
带你去安全的地方  好吗
We're gonna get you safe, okay?
别担心  好吗  伸手
Don't you worry, okay? Give me your hands.
谢谢配合
Thank you so much.
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
-谢谢你  -到底发生什么事了
- Thank you. - What the hell's going on?
请尽快离开这里
Just get out of here, okay?
-这雾是怎么回事  -快进屋去
- What's this fog doing? - Just get inside now!
快  快
Go, go!
快来  萨姆  萨姆
Come on. Sam, Sam.
别管他们了
Let them go!
艾尔哈特探员  无线电失效了
Agent Ehart? Radio's dead.
有胶带吗
You have any duct tape?
萨姆  萨姆
Sam? Sam?!
(无信号)
治安官  我们试试看能不能把无线电修好
Sheriff, let's see if we can't fix that radio of yours.
迪恩
Dean?
你听到了吗
You hear that?
迪恩
Dean.
萨姆
Sam!
伙计们  我们得待在一起  明白吗
Folks, we need to stay together, okay?
萨姆
Sam?
不  不  别过来  不要
No, no, get back! Don't!
天呐  他被感染了
My God, he's infected.
所有人  都到里面去
Everybody, get inside!
都来
Everybody.
快  快进去  快
Come on. Let's move. Come on.
快来  我们走  快进来
Come on! Let's go! Get in here!
不  我不会离开我弟弟的
No, I'm not leaving my brother.
你真是个很棒的编辑  梅塔特隆
You know, you really are a terrific editor, Metatron.
我是个糟糕的作家
Well, I was a terrible writer.
烂透了的上帝
A worse God.
幸好我还是有所长的
It's good I got something going for me.
知道吗  我必须承认
Yeah, you know, I have to say,
我完全没料到你会黑化
I didn't see the whole evil-turn thing coming.
你为什么要试图成为我啊
Why did you try to be me?
那只是可悲地求关注而已
That was just a sad, pathetic cry for attention.
你想吸引谁的注意啊
Whose attention were you trying to get?
你的
Yours.
你是光
You are light...
是美
and beauty.
是创造
Creation.
是怒火
Wrath.
是毁灭也是救赎
Damnation and salvation.
我不在乎自己是否只是
And I don't care if I was just
离门最近的那个天使而已
the angel nearest the door.
你选择了我
You picked me.
你的光辉照耀在了我身上  我
Your light shined on me -- me!
还有你的温暖
Oh, and the warmth.
但之后你离开了我
But then you left me.
你离开了我们所有人
You left all of us.
向你祈祷的不止是地球上的那帮呆子
It wasn't just the saps on Earth who were praying to you.
天使也会祈祷
The angels prayed, too.
我也祈祷  每天都祈祷
And so did I -- every day.
我知道
I know.
你想写出有史以来最畅销的自传
You want to write the best-selling autobiography of all time,
你就得给我个解释
you explain to me --
告诉我你为何抛弃了我
tell me why you abandoned me.
抛弃了我们
Us.
因为你让我失望了
Because you disappointed me.
你们所有人都让我失望了
You all disappointed me.
不  听着
No, look.
我知道我令你失望
I know I'm a disappointment,
但你关于人的看法是错的
but you're wrong about humanity.
人是你最伟大的造物
They are your greatest creation
因为他们比你强
because they're better than you are.
没错  人类软弱  欺骗  偷盗
Yeah, sure, they're weak and they cheat and steal
破坏  辜负希望
and...destroy and disappoint.
可他们也会给予  创造
But they also give and create
懂得享乐  懂得去爱
and they sing and dance and love.
最重要的是  他们永不言弃
And above all, they never give up.
而你恰恰相反
But you do.
萨姆
Sam!
听我说
Hey, listen to me!
-萨姆  -我们做不到的
- Sam! - We're not gonna make it.
不不  不能放弃
No, no, no. There's no quitting here.
-我们做不到的  -萨姆  听我说
- We're never gonna make it. - Sam, listen to me.
你是因为雾的关系才会这么说
That's not you talking, it's the fog.
你本打算选阿玛拉  而不是我
You were gonna choose Amara over me.
不是其他的一切
Over everything.
-萨姆  别  -对不起
- Sam, no! - Look, I'm sorry.
我不是真心的  迪恩
I didn't mean that, Dean.
我撑不住的  你快走
I can't fight this. You got to go.
在你也被感染之前快走
You got to get out before you're infected.
趁我还没有伤害你
Go before I hurt you!
我永远不会抛下你的
No, I'm not leaving you -- ever!
好了
Okay.
停下
Stop this!
听见没有  混蛋
You hear me, you dick?!
别  别  别
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
看着我
Hey, hey, look at me.
看着我  有我在呢
Look at me. I'm right here.
有我在呢
I'm right here.
没事了  不会有事的
Okay, it's okay. It's all right.
我在呢
I'm right here.
我之前撒了谎
You know, I lied before.
我其实没亲自学会弹吉他
I didn't really learn to play guitar.
而是直接给了自己那能力
I just kind of... gave myself the ability.
"学"法语时也是这么干的
I did the same when I "learned" French.
说实话的感觉真轻松
Man, this whole honesty thing -- it's really freeing.
来吧
Come on.
看看新出炉的故事
Take a look at the new pages.
你想看的  对吧
You know you want to.
算了吧
I think I'll pass.
你会喜欢的
I think you're really gonna like them.
你说得对  有点高了
You're right. It -- It's a little high.
好吧
All right.
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
*若我有双*
*If I had wings*
*诺亚之鸽的翅膀*
*Like Noah's dove*
*我会飞过河流*
*I'd fly up the river*
*来到爱人身旁*
*To the one I love*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
*亲爱的*
*Oh, honey*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
*有位故人*
*I knew a man*
*个子高高*
*Who was long and tall*
*飞奔的速度*
*He moved his body*
*像门加农炮*
*Like a cannonball*
*望你一切安好*
*Oh, fare thee well*
*亲爱的*
*Oh, honey*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
*那一晚*
*Remember one night*
*烟雨蒙蒙*
*In the drizzling rain*
*我的心房*
*And around my heart*
*一阵剧痛*
*I felt an aching pain*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
*亲爱的*
*Oh, honey*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well, mm-mm*
*不久之后*
*One of these days*
*那一天终将到来*
*It won't be long*
*你会呼唤我的名字*
*You'll call my name*
*我却已不在*
*And I'll be gone*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
*亲爱的*
*Oh, honey*
*望你一切安好*
*Fare thee well*
-还好吗  -谢谢
- You okay? - Thanks.
妈妈
Mom!
我们大概该谈谈
We should probably talk.